Finding Aid for Henry W. Hatch photograph collection, 1914, 1940s-1950s and undated
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Henry W. Hatch photograph collection 1814, 1940s-1950s and undated 1947-1955
Hatch, Henry W.
0.4 linear feet and 1 outsize folder
00123 Aa 2 UAm
Henry Hatch was equipment manager for the University of Michigan Athletic Department, 1921-1964. Photographs of University of Michigan athletes (chiefly football players) and coaches and celebrities, photograph (1951) of Hatch at work in the University of Michigan athletic equipment area, photograph of Hatch as a child; also photograph (1914) of Ann Arbor, Mich., fire engine next to an interurban car.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received in 2013from Pat Hatch. (Donor No. 4338 )
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Henry Hatch was equipment manager for the University of Michigan Athletic Department from 1921 to 1964, working with Athletic Directors Fielding Yost and Fritz Crisler and seven football coaches. Hatch started the Michigan's tradition of retiring football jerseys when he decided after the 1927 season that Bennie Oosterbaan's #47 would never be issued again.
Hatch was born June 13, 1900 and died April 4, 1964.
The Hatch collection consists of photos acquired by Hatch over the course of his 44 year association with the U-M Athletic Department. The collection includes portraits and posed action photos of football players, mainly ca. 1940-1955, some of which are autographed to Hatch; photos documenting the football team's train trips to the 1948 and 1951 Rose Bowl games and several Hollywood photos from the track team's 1935 trip to California. There are miscellaneous photos of coaches and players from other sports, posed photos of Miss Michigan 1948 on a ski hill and a 1914 photo of an Ann Arbor fire engine next to an interurban car.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Hatch, Henry W.; Athletics--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Fire engines and equipment--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Sports.; University of Michigan--Football.
Photographs.
- Photographs
  - Ann Arbor Fire Engine, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Basketball (Box 1)
    (includes Coaches Franklin Cappon and Bennie Oosterbaan, Coach Bill Perigo)
  - Football
    - Coaches Harry Kipke and Bennie Oosterbaan (Box 1)
    - Football game action and practice (Box 1)
    - Football players (Box 1)
    - ca. 1940-1954
      (posed action and headshots, including: Allis, Harry; Barr, Terry; Ceithaml, George; Daley, Bill; Evashevski, Forest; Franks, Julius; Greene, John; Hirsch, Elroy; Ingalls, Bob; Kempthorn, Dick; Hilkene, Bruce; Krager, George; McWilliams, Dick; Maentz, Tom; Monsen, Tony; Nelson, Davey; Peterson, Don; Peterson, Tom; Petoskey, Jack; Ponsetto, Joe with Fritz Crisler; Pregulman, Merv; Pritula, Bill; Rifenburg, Dick; Rogers, Joseph; Teninga, Wally; Tinkham, David; Tomasi, Dom; Westfall, Robert; Wisniewski, Irv; Wistert, Al; unidentified (9))
      - Bob Brown, captain, 1924 (Box 1)
        (posed with game balls and with (stuffed) Wolverine on a leash)
      - Tom Harmon (Box 1)
      - Ron Kramer (Box 1)
    - Football Team photos, 1945-1949 and 1964 (Box 1)
      (Rentschler studio prints, plus 1945 full squad)
    - Football Ticket Office staff, ca 1940 (Box 1)
    - Rose Bowl, 1950 (Box 1)
      (photos of train trip, 1 game action photo)
    - Architectural Rendering of new Michigan Stadium Press Box, ca. 1955 (Box 1)
  - Miss Michigan, skiing publicity photos, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Henry Hatch with others (Box 1)
    (includes photo with Little Brown Jug)
  - Track Team Trip to California, 1935 (Box 1)
    (2 photos of team posed at Fox Studio and movie set and Steve Farrell and Ralph Aigler with actress Alice Faye)
  - Photo Album
    - Rose Bowl, 1948 (Box 1)
      (photos of train trip, arrival in Pasadena)
  - Outsize Photos (Box UAm)
    (includes portrait of Hatch as a child, photos of Hatch at work in the equipment room, Bob Chappuis, Tom Harmon, football team at Willow Run for the 1940 flight to California, autographed photos of Bob Hope and Joe E. Brown.)
Related Material
A scrapbook maintained by Hatch's daughter, Patricia Hatch, contains football clippings, tickets and ephemera from U-M bowl games, 1948-1976. It is cataloged as the Patricia Hatch scrapbook, 1947-1976.